# KHAI NGUYEN

## khai.nguyen@outlook.com | github.com/khaister

A Senior Software Engineer with 8+ years in object-oriented software engineering, applied to the creation of complex software systems and tackling technical challenges; strengths in working collaboratively with technical and business teams to produce outstanding software products from design to launch.

## WORK EXPERIENCE

#### Senior Software Engineer at blinkhealth.com from MAR 2022 to PRESENT

- Build the core Web API backend service for managing prescriptions
- Integrate a Django RESTful web API into the proprietary pharmacy software for insurance eligibility and claim purposes
- Build software on top of an automation workflow engine (Camunda Platform) to integrate with external provider for drug prescription data flow according to business requirements

## Senior Software Engineer at apartments.com from AUG 2019 to MAR 2022

- Designed and implement Messaging system using RESTful Web API and background service components, deployed to AWS-hosted VPC
- Built a web service from scratch to support Online Tour Scheduling functionalities for multi-family communities
- · On-boarded new team members onto various projects within Apartments.com codebase
- Coached/transferred knowledge to junior developers on software engineering in general, Apartments.com domain knowledge, and development process
- Led technical interviews during hiring process to evaluate potential candidates for team
- Led/collaborated with team members at all seniority levels and coordinated with stakeholders to unblock process and ensure features were delivered as specified and in a timely manner

## Software Development Engineer at quickbridge.com from OCT 2018 to JUL 2019

- Built & maintained middle-tier web services using the latest ASP.NET Framework for sending SMS messages via Twilio API within a 3-month turnaround time
- Designed & implemented the SMS UI/UX using Angular 4 for internal CRM web application

#### **Software Engineer** at cudirect.com from JUN 2015 to SEP 2018

- Implemented features for a WPF application, along with the backend Web API, for loan & account management purposes
- Oversaw version control system migration from TFVC to Git repositories, including training 20 team members & promoting best practices, effectively increased development velocity and collaboration across 5 teams
- Led release deployment effort by coordinating teams to finalize software components for production release

#### **SKILLS**

- Backend Django, Python, PostgreSQL, SQL Server, MySQL, REST APIs, .NET Core/C#
- Cloud AWS (ECS, Lambda, SNS, SQS, DynamoDB)
- Frontend TypeScript/JavaScript, React, Styled Components
- DevOps macOS, CI/CD, Git, GitHub Actions, Docker, Bash, Agile

## **EDUCATION**

**B.Sc.** *cum laude* in **Biochemistry** with **Computer Science** California State University, Long Beach (2015)